Contact

verma.shikha2521@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/shikhaverma-94648880 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

SQL

Tableau

Microsoft Excel

Certifications

Creating Interactive Dashboards in Tableau 10

Tableau Essential Training
Software testing - foundation level

Shikha verma

Manager - Data Analytics, Reliance retail ltd. Bengaluru

Summary

Skilled data analyst with 5.3 years of industry experience in collecting, organizing, interpreting, and disseminating various types of data and statistical figures. Energetic presenter and confident communicator with the ability to circulate information in a way that is clear, efficient, and beneficial for end users. Proficient knowledge in analytics, statistics and mathematics. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tool for effective analysis of data. Creative in finding solutions to problems and determining modifications for optimal use of organizational data. Expert at providing realistic projections and establishing various scenarios to determine viable process strategies to utilize. Organized and timely in providing staff, departmental members, and executive management with reports on specific data findings and their impact on organizational growth and success.

Experience

Reliance Retail
Manager- Data analytics
June 2018 - Present (2 years 3 months)
Bangalore

- Managing the data for both retail and E. Com business. (AJIO, Trends, Project Eve, Payless, Footprint, etc)
- Collecting, organizing and interpreting data from sales, marketing departments to use in establishing organizational structure. Also using SAP, Tableau for fetching required data.
- Organize, extrapolate, and disseminate data across departments to be used for drawing conclusions about the current business health and the focus area for improvement.
- Present detailed reports about the meaning of gathered data to members of management and help them identify scenarios utilizing modifications in the data.

• Reporting monthly data analysis findings in the form of dashboards to upper management to use in making organizational decisions. (Dashboards made using EXCEL and Tableau or Power BI)

Amazon

Data Analyst

June 2017 - June 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

- Managing huge data especially the loss data.
- Coordinating with stakeholders on regular basis and understanding their requirement for data and providing the same.
- Analyzing and tracking the data for top contributors in loss and deep diving into the data to collect strong data points.
- Created Dashboards to visualize the overall loss trend using the tool like Tableau and Excel.
- Successfully interpreting the data to draw conclusion for managerial actions and strategy.
- Presenting findings and data to the team to improve strategies and operations
- Optimize data collection procedures and generate reports on weekly, monthly and quarterly basis.
- Using SQL (My SQL, Datanet (ETL) and Amazon Redshit) for fetching data.
- · Identified data requirements and isolated data elements
- Good knowledge of Business flow(Amazon's Operation).

Navisite

Client technical operations (Testing engineer)
July 2016 - May 2017 (11 months)

Gurgaon, Haryana, India

- Communicating with the client to understand the data requirements and providing them with the analysis to support their decision
- Using SQL to fetch the data(MY SQL)
- Analyzing the fetched data weekly. Providing the clients with the trend of their business
- Monitoring incoming and outgoing data traffic for AJE business.
- Daily reporting of all the analysis done.
- Making reports on excel on weekly basis.
- Also conducting functional and non- functional testing using testing techniques to test the accounts.

 Managing client's accounts and making sure that accounts are error free by performing continuous test. Testing the website.

Binary Semantics Ltd.
Analyst (Google Hotel Ads)
December 2014 - June 2016 (1 year 7 months)
Gurgaon, India

- Business analysis using client's data to help them know how the market is performing for them
- Working with the partners to provide recommendations and solutions for more visibility of ads to users, by knowing their marketing regions and auction strategies.
- Deep dive QA of partner feeds/data to ensure alignment with Google standards, running queries in SQL to find data inaccuracies & areas of improvement.
- Fetch the partner data from their server location and run weekly/fortnightly. Analyzing the performance for the partners and sending out a report to them on weekly basis.
- Prepare charts in MS-Excel to demonstrate feed performance in a week-onweek basis.
- Develop dashboards and quality reports in Google Sheets for integration partners and communicate issues to them.
- Manipulate and analyze complex, high-volume, high dimensional data from various sources to highlight quality issues.

Education

kiit college of engineering
Bachelor of Technology (BTech), Computer Science · (2010 - 2014)

dhanbad public school twelth, science · (2009 - 2010)